<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Qt on Threads Of Life</title>
    <link>https://karanbalkar.com/categories/qt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Qt on Threads Of Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 14:37:49 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://karanbalkar.com/categories/qt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Base64 encoding and decoding using Qt 5 framework</title>
      <link>https://karanbalkar.com/posts/base64-encoding-decoding-using-qt5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 14:37:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karanbalkar.com/posts/base64-encoding-decoding-using-qt5/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
In one of my previous posts, we had learnt how to configure and setup Qt for Windows. Base64 is basically a method using which we can encode binary data into a character set in order to transmit the data without any loss or modification of the contents. It is a group of similar binary-to-text encoding schemes that represent binary data in an ASCII string format by translating it into a radix-64 representation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sending Http Request Using Qt 5 framework</title>
      <link>https://karanbalkar.com/posts/sending-http-request-using-qt5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 11:20:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karanbalkar.com/posts/sending-http-request-using-qt5/</guid>
      <description>HTTP (Hypertext Transfer Protocol) works as a request-response protocol between a client and server. A web browser may be the client, and an application on a computer that hosts a web site may be the server. For example, a client (browser) submits an HTTP request to the server and then the server returns a response to the client. The response contains status information about the request as well as the requested content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Qt</title>
      <link>https://karanbalkar.com/posts/getting-started-with-qt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 11:03:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karanbalkar.com/posts/getting-started-with-qt/</guid>
      <description>Hi guys,
Qt is a cross-platform application framework used extensively for developing non-GUI programs and consoles for servers. It is written in C++ and works on major platforms including Android, iOS, Windows and more recently Sailfish MeeGo Linux. There exists three versions of Qt available on each of these platforms, namely:
GUI Framework – commercial entry level GUI edition, stripped of network and database support (formerly named &amp;ldquo;Desktop Light&amp;rdquo;)
Full Framework – complete commercial edition Open Source – complete Open Source edition</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parsing JSON using Qt 5 framework</title>
      <link>https://karanbalkar.com/posts/parsing-json-using-qt5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 10:49:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karanbalkar.com/posts/parsing-json-using-qt5/</guid>
      <description>Hello friends!
In one of my previous posts, we had seen how to send a HTTP request using Qt. The response we got then was a JSON string. JSON is a subset of the object literal notation of JavaScript. It is basically a lightweight data-interchange format making it easy for humans to read and write. A JSON is build on two structures namely,
 A collection of name/value pairs. In various languages, this is realized as an object, record, struct, dictionary, hash table, keyed list or associative array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zipping and unzipping files using Qt 5 framework</title>
      <link>https://karanbalkar.com/posts/zipping-unzipping-files-using-qt5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 08:38:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karanbalkar.com/posts/zipping-unzipping-files-using-qt5/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone!
Qt provides a QByteArray class that can be used to store raw bytes and traditional 8-bit terminated strings. Moreover, Qt also provides the QString class to store string data. QString is mainly used throughout the Qt API.
Through this post, we will learn how to zip and unzip files using Qt. We will create a sample text file containing a message as follows,
demo.txt
This is a demo to zip and unzip files using Qt framework Pre-requisites: Qt Creator, MinGW compiler for Windows (64 bit)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
